<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serverless Notebook!</title>
    <link>https://imewish.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Serverless Notebook!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imewish.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing Serverless Applications With Serverless Artillery</title>
      <link>https://imewish.github.io/posts/load-testing-serverless-sls-artillery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imewish.github.io/posts/load-testing-serverless-sls-artillery/</guid>
      <description>Load testing is an important part when you are designing any type of application, whether it is traditional EC2 based or container-based or a complete serverless application.
Why is Load Testing important? Load testing will help us to find the following
- How fast is the system
- How much load can the system handle
- Under what conditions will the system fail
- Determine our application’s capabilities by measuring its response time, throughput, CPU utilization, latency, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URL redirects with AWS S3 and Cloudfront</title>
      <link>https://imewish.github.io/posts/2019-12-15-url-redirects-with-aws-s3-and-cloudfront/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imewish.github.io/posts/2019-12-15-url-redirects-with-aws-s3-and-cloudfront/</guid>
      <description>Hosting a static website with S3 is awesome! It is Faster, Cheaper, Zero maintenance.
In this article, we will see how to do URL redirects on a website hosted with AWS S3 and Cloudfront.
There was a scenario which I was faced once in my company, One of our websites had deleted some old content and replaced it with new content and URL. And when people who google search for that particular content they get the old URL which doest exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Deployment Of Lambda Functions Using Serverless Framework, AWS CodePipeline</title>
      <link>https://imewish.github.io/posts/2019-11-23-automating-deployment-of-lambda-functions-using-serverless-framework-aws-codepipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imewish.github.io/posts/2019-11-23-automating-deployment-of-lambda-functions-using-serverless-framework-aws-codepipeline/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we will set up a very simple REST API endpoint with the serverless framework, AWS Lambda, and API Gateway and deploy it to AWS Lambda with Github, AWS Codepipeline, Codebuild
1. Install the Serverless Framework npm install serverless -g 2. Create a project serverless create --template aws-nodejs --path serverless-nodejs-api This will create two files handler.js and serveless.yml
&#39;use strict&#39;; module.exports.api = async event =&amp;gt; { return { statusCode: 200, body: JSON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>https://imewish.github.io/about-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imewish.github.io/about-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.com/russross/blackfriday https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>